Southwest Folklore Center Cassette Recordings Collection, 1975-1995
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Grand Canyon Cowboy Band: 50th anniversary concert, tape 1, Grand Canyon Cowboy Band, 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From Acquisitions Inventory: Individuals recorded are Warren Miller, Sam Fenner, John Bradley, Slim Kite, and Marvin Bennett. Contains re-creation of a night of entertainment at the Bright Angel Lodge, Grand Canyon, in 1935...; SWF 89.27/C.12
- Grand Canyon Cowboy Band: 50th anniversary concert, tape 2, Grand Canyon Cowboy Band, 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From Acquisitions Inventory: Individuals recorded are Warren Miller, Sam Fenner, John Bradley, Slim Kite, and Marvin Bennett. Contains re-creation of a night of entertainment at the Bright Angel Lodge, Grand Canyon, in 1935...; SWF 89.27/C.13
- Grand Canyon Cowboy Band: 50th anniversary concert, tape 3, Grand Canyon Cowboy Band, 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From Acquisitions Inventory: Individuals recorded are Warren Miller, Sam Fenner, John Bradley, Slim Kite, and Marvin Bennett. Contains re-creation of a night of entertainment at the Bright Angel Lodge, Grand Canyon, in 1935...; SWF 89.27/C.14
- Grand Canyon Cowboy Band: 50th anniversary concert, tape 4, Grand Canyon Cowboy Band, 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From Acquisitions Inventory: Individuals recorded are Warren Miller, Sam Fenner, John Bradley, Slim Kite, and Marvin Bennett. Contains re-creation of a night of entertainment at the Bright Angel Lodge, Grand Canyon, in 1935...; SWF 89.27/C.15
- Eloise Turner: Oral history [life at the] Grand Canyon, 1949-1957, Turner, Eloise, 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From Acquisitions Inventory: Eloise Turner recalls her life at the Grand Canyon as the wife of Sam Turner, an agent at the Santa Fe depot.; SWF 89.27/C.16
- H.P. Morgan sings and preaches [at Sedona], Morgan, H.P., 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From Acquisitions Inventory: Side 1: country songs... Side 2: sermons delivered in Sedona, Arizona...; SWF 89.27/C.17
- Gail Gardner with Horse Sense, Gardner, Gail and Horse Sense, 1985 October 5; [October 5, 1985]; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From Acquisitions Inventory: Contains songs, stories, and poems...; SWF 89.27/C.18
- Mayer Cowboy Concert, tape 1, Mayer, 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From Acquisitions Inventory: Individuals recorded are Glen Ohrlin, Marivn Bennett, Slim Kite, and Everett Brisendine...Contains cowboy poems, songs, and stories...; SWF 89.27/C.19
- Mayer Cowboy Concert, tape 2, Mayer, 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From Acquisitions Inventory: Individuals recorded are Glen Ohrlin, Marivn Bennett, Slim Kite, and Everett Brisendine...Contains cowboy poems, songs, and stories...; SWF 89.27/C.20
- Bud Brown sings and reminisces, Brown, Bud, 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From Acquisitions Inventory: Warren Miller interviews Bud Brown...Contains narrative about Brown's decision to come west, as well as cowboy songs and stories...; SWF 89.27/C.21
- Marvin Bennett's personal tapes, tape 1, Bennett, Marvin, 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From Acquisitions Inventory: Individuals recorded are Marvin Bennett, Grant Bennett, and Marie Bennett...Contains cowboy songs and fiddle tunes and Grant Bennett talking about his life...; SWF 89.27/C.22
- Interview with Lopez brothers, Lopez brothers, 1989 September 4; Arivaca, AZ., September 4, 1989; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: Interview with the Lopez brothers about the Arivaca horse races...Collector: James S. Griffith and Richard Morales; SWF 89.28/C.1
- Fiddlin' inferno, Wurst, Brian, 1985; Wurst Productions, p1985; 1 sound cassette (30 minutes) analog, stereo; NOTES: Brian Wurst plays fiddle, mandolin, and tenor guitar...Lonesome Cherokee -- Kansas City Kitty -- Julianna's waltz -- Brownskin gal -- Chuck in the bush -- Star of the County Down -- Southern bells of Nashville -- Arkansas traveler -- Sweet bunch of daisies -- Salt Creek -- Forked deer -- Whistler's waltz -- Grey Eagle --; SWF 90.1/C.1
- Waltzing fire, Wurst, Brian, 1984; Wurst Productions, p1984; 1 sound cassette (30 min.), analog, stereo; NOTES: Photograph of Brian Wurst on cover... Wurst plays fiddle, mandolins, guitar, and bass... Chancellor's waltz -- 40 years ago waltz -- Gardenia waltz -- Cottonwoods waltz -- Goodnight waltz -- Trash waltz -- Dreamer's waltz -- Skater's waltz -- Gold and silver waltz -- Velvet waltz -- Ook pic -- Waltz across Texas --; SWF 90.1/C.2
- Fiddlin' fire, Wurst, Brian, 1984; Wurst Productions, p1984; 1 sound cassette (30 min.), analog, stereo; NOTES: Brian Wurst plays fiddle, mandolin, guitar, and bass... Sally Gooden -- Yellow rose waltz -- Maple leaf reel -- Sally Johnson -- Mark's waltz -- Clarinet polka -- Soppin' the gravy -- Mexicali rose waltz -- Black and white rag -- Dusty Miller -- Festival waltz -- Gold rush --; SWF 90.1/C.3
- Apache, Palmer, Macklin, 1982; [Washington, D.C.]: The Library of Congress Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Recorded and edited by Willard Rhodes, [p1982?]; 1 sound cassette, analog; Music of the American Indian; NOTES: Cover illustration: Apache Fire Dance, by Al Momaday...Issued as a series of 10 recordings...Accompanying material in acquisition file...Performers include: Macklin Palmer; Sinew L. Riley; Clarence Peaches; David Dazen; Sam Haozous; Blossom Haozous; James Hume...Crown dance song -- Crown dance song -- Sunrise dance song -- Sunrise dance song -- Love song -- Love song -- Fire dance song -- Moccasin game song -- Love song -- Song from the girl's puberty rite -- Song from the girl's puberty rite --; SWF 90.5/C.3
- Indian songs of today, Indian Young People, 1982; [Washington, D.C.]: The Library of Congress Motion Picture Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Recorded and edited by Willard Rhodes, [p1982]; 1 sound cassette, analog; Music of the American Indian; NOTES: Cover illustration: water color, Three eagle dancers, by Woody Crumbo...Issued as series of 10 recordings... Accompanying material in acquisition file 90.5...Seminole: Duck dance song -- Creek lullaby -- Potawatomi song -- Sioux wan dance song -- Sioux rabbit dance song -- Navajo squaw dance song -- Navajo squaw dance song -- Navojo song of happiness -- Tewa basket dance song -- Round dance song -- Buffalo dance song -- Modern love song -- Kiowa round dance song -- Kiowa buffalo dance song -- Feather dance song -- Two Cherokee Christian hymns -- Stomp dance song -- Three modern love songs -- Tlingit paddling song --; SWF 90.5/C.4
- Legends in Levis, Trimble, Marshall and the Overdub Band, 1990; Scottsdale, AZ., Silver Bullet Productions, published by Reata Publishing Company, Scottsdale, AZ., p1990; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: Photograph of Marshall Trimble on cover... Cover contains biographical information on Trimble and commentary on the songs and poems... Performers include: Marshall Trimble, vocals, instruments; Pete Willman, instruments; Lisa Owens, vocals... Musical arrangements by Mark Prentice and Pete Willman.. Sierry Petes (2:57) -- Moonshine steer (3:10) -- Bad brahma bull (5:40) -- Strawberry roan (3:21) -- From town (2:50) -- Legends in Levis (2:20) -- Windy Bill (2:56) -- The Zebra dun (4:39) -- A good place for a Hell (3:20) -- Dude wrangler (5:17) -- High chin Bob (3:00) -- Yavapai Pete (3:47) --; SWF 90.8/C.1
- First 29 Navajo code talker, Nez, Chester, 1990 August 8; Albuquerque, NM., August 8, 1990; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: Interview by Zonnie Gorman with Chester Nez...In Navajo...Collector: Zonnie Gorman.; SWF 90.14/C.1.T
- Arm and Hammer: Original and traditional music, Duff, Anna and Stefan George, 1989; Tucson, AZ., Marsound, p1989; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: Photo of musicians on cover... Musicians: Anna Duff, hammered ducimer; Stefan George, guitar, keyboards and lap steel...Mike Reinhard, engineer...Ready or not -- Texas quickstep -- Mabel St. rag -- Jeff Davis -- Necropolis -- Vera Cruz -- Two-lane waltz -- Zephyr -- Jerusalem Ridge --; SWF 91.3/C.1
- [Interview with Lou Castellum and Virginia Islas], Castellum, Lou and Virginia Islas, 1991 January 28; Tucson, AZ., January 28, 1991; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: Interview by James S. Griffith with Lou Castellum and Virginia Islas concerning cascarones, a decorated eggshell and tissue paper folk art item of Mexico. Collector: James S. Griffith.; SWF 91.11/C.1
- Southside Presbyterian Church Choir, Tucson, Arizona, vol. II, Southside Presbyterian Church Choir, 1990; Tucson, AZ., Jim Brady Studios, p1990; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From cover, "Dedicated to the memory of John Ashwood"... Rose Johnson, director and pianist... Susan Parrott, producer... Choir members listed on cover.. O it is Jesus -- I love to praise Him -- Twelve gates -- We shall walk -- Swing low, sweet chariot -- Lift Him up -- Lead me, guide me -- Love has no borders -- You must be born again -- Call Him up -- Mother's amazing grace -- There's a bright side -- Up above my head -- Wade in the water -- Be not afraid --; SWF 91.12/C.1
- [Interview with Mrs. Margaret Redondo], Redondo, Margaret, 1991 February 7; Saguarita, AZ., February 7, 1991; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: Cassette tape interview (one side) with Mrs. Margaret Redondo near Madera Canyon, AZ. by James S. Griffith on February 7, 1991...More information available in acquisitions file, 91.13/C.1...Topics include: an account of a divine intervention (Lady in Blue) in the 1887 siege of Caborca--a treasure story around Madera Canyon--a story of a hermit treasure hunter on Elephant Butte of Santa Rita Mountains--a short account of a tradition that Teddy Roosevelt visited old pals in Madera Canyon. Collector: James S. Griffith.; SWF 91.13/C.1
- First 29 Navajo code talker, tape 1, Brown, John Jr., 1991 August 6; August 6, 1991; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: Interview with John Brown, Jr....In Navajo...; SWF 91.27/C.1
- First 29 Navajo code talker, tape 2, Brown, John Jr., 1991 August 6; August 6, 1991; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: Interview with John Brown, Jr....In Navajo...; SWF 91.27/C.2
- Plegaris al Santo Niño de Atocha y a la Virgen de San Juan, Los Rieleros, 1991; 1991; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: Original tape purchased in Plateros, Zacatecas, Mexico, June, 1991...Plegaria al Santo Niño (Domingo Turrubiate) -- Corrido de Plateros (Antonio Martinez) -- Alabanzas al Santo Niño (Dominio Publico) -- Mañanitas al Santo Niño (Domingo Turrubiate) -- Mi Plateros (Gilberto Castro) -- Virgen de San Juan (Domingo Turrubiate) -- San Juanita (Domingo Turrubiate) -- Mañanitas a la Virgen de San Juan (Domingo Turrubiate) -- San Juan de los Lagos, Jal. (Domingo Turrubiate) -- Juan Paulo II (Antonio Martinez) --; SWF 91.30/C.1
- Arizona Dance Hands: The best in Western music, Arizona Dance Hands, 1986; [1986?]; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From label, "An evening at Li'l Abner's with Dean Armstrong, Billy Burkes and Edsel Smith, recorded live"...Sketch of group on cover dated 1986...; SWF 91.31/C.1
- Remembering how it used to be, Evans, Ray and Skelly Boyd, 1991; p1991; 1 cassette tape, analog; NOTES: Cowboy poetry recited by Roy Evans; Shelly Boyd, guitar and music...Phantom trooper (Bruce Kiskaddon)--When you've finished shipping cattle in the fall (Bruce Kiskaddon)--The Rogue steer (Henry Nibbs)--Buck (unknown)--The Untold story (Roy Evans)--Thoughts of a wrangler (Roy Evans)--; SWF 91.34/C.1
- Salt River Ramblers, Salt River Ramblers, 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From container, "one non-commercial, audition-type cassette"... In the acquisitions file there is a flyer for the Salt River Ramblers Bluegrass Band with a photograph of the band. Band members are listed: Herb Jackson, guitar; Jerry Jenott, mandolin; Gary Cole, banjo; Fred Tanner, bass...; SWF 91.37/C.1
- Navajo traditional two-step and skip songs, Sweethearts of Navajoland, 1991; Phoenix, AZ., Distributed by Canyon Records Productions, Sweethearts of Navajoland, p1991; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: Photograph of Sweethearts of Navajoland on cover... Singers include: Lillian Ashely, manager; Darleen Juan; Linda Hardy; Marlene Begay; Lena Hardy... Two-step songs: Waiting around for me -- Do you remember? -- You're my only sweetheart -- Back to Towac -- Hopi partner -- Blackfoot followed me back -- Skip songs: I followed you to the dances -- One night out -- You left for no reason -- Your fault -- Albuquerque Indian finals -- Santa Domingo hosteen --; SWF 92.2/C.1
- Chicken scratch, The Braves, 1991; Phoenix, AZ., Canyon Records Productions, p1991; 1 sound cassette, analog, vol.3; NOTES: Photograph of The Braves on cover... Musicians include: Neal Norris, guitar; Alex Cruz, accordian; Marvin Juan, percussion; Donnie Manuel, drums; Jason Wood, saxophone; Gilbert Jose, bass... T.G.'s waila -- Haskell chote -- Eloy cumgia -- Forgotten chote -- Leah's waila -- Stan's jam -- De Mos Gracias -- E.M.C. cumbia -- Flats waila -- Mission chote -- Cereus cumbia -- Ak-Chin two step --; SWF 92.2/C.2
- Southern scratch, Chicken scratch, 1991; Phoenix, AZ., Canyon Records Productions, Executive Producer, Raymond A. Boley, p1991; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: Cover photograph of Chicken Scratch... Musicians include: Ron Joaquin, bass guitar; Ben Jose, accordian and sax; Rupert Vavages, accordian and guitar; Jose Velasco, drums; Jesse Puentes, guitar and bass guitar; Carlos Rodriquez, percussion; Isaac Vavages, sax... Recorded by Allen Moore... Monterrey polka -- Let's get cereus mazurka -- Southern babes waila -- City life cumbia -- Paula chote -- Brass monkey waila -- Angelita polka -- Matador cumbia -- Old Faithful mazurka -- El Circo polka -- Please stay chote -- Gypsy cumbia --; SWF 92.2/C.3
- Gu-Achi fiddlers: Old time O'odham fiddle music, volume 2, Gu-Achi Fiddlers, 1991; Phoenix, AZ., Canyon Records Productions, p1991; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: On cover, photos of performers... Performers include: Elliot Johnson; Wilford Mendoza; Lester Vavages; Mike Francisco; Gerald Leos, Sr.... Lonnie polka -- First choice two-step -- Luz mazurka -- Purple lilies polka -- Big shoes two-step -- Saint Rose of Lima mazurka -- Cababie polka -- Second time in San Xavier two-step -- Cowlic mazurka -- Celeya polka -- Manacho loco two-step -- Tohono special polka --; SWF 92.2/C.4
- Indian humor, Toelken, Barre, 1992 March 27; March 27, 1992; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From acquisition inventory, "Indian Humor," a talk given by Barre Toelken on March 27, 1992, at the University of Arizona... Introduction by Dr. Larry Evers"...; SWF 92.5/C.1
- More songs of Lalo Guerrero, Guerrero, Lalo, 1992; 1992; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: In English and Spanish...No Chicanos on T.V. -- To all the girls -- Wake up Chicanos -- Mexican mamas -- Mr. Jackson -- Zoot suit boogie -- Cancion Mexicana -- Nunca jamas -- El tartamudo -- Viejo barrio -- El Chicano -- Muy sabroso blues --; SWF 92.13/C.1
- Frontier fiddler, Kartchner, K.C., 1990; Tucson, AZ., University of Arizona Press, p1990; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: Companion to K.C. Kartchner's autobiography, Frontier Fiddler, published by the University of Arizona Press, 1990...Rattlesnake -- Tom and Jerry -- Black Hills waltz -- Bobtailed mule -- Birds in the brook -- Tom Wagner -- Dream of heaven waltz -- Cacklin' hen -- Buckin' dun -- Snowbird in the Ashbank -- Walk along John to Kansas -- Grey Eagle -- Eighth of January -- Flowers of Edinburgh -- Pete Marker waltz -- Waggoner -- Sally Johnson -- Billy in the lowground -- Long ways to Holbrook -- Sweet O'Weaver -- Wednesday waltz -- Leather britches -- The old hen she cackled -- The drunkard's hiccups -- Lost goose -- Pinedale waltz -- Johnny Blevin's tune --; SWF 92.16/C.1
- Corrido de Manuel Pacheco o Presidente tres veces, Fernandez, Celestino, 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: On cover,"music by Guillermo Saenz"... Arranged by Guillermo and Raul Saenz... Transcription available in file, 92.17/M-1... In Spanish...; SWF 92.17/C.1
- [Apache song], Wilson, Ruth Longor and Chesley Goseyum Wilson, 1991; [1991?]; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From acquisition file..."Western Apache songs and music; waterdrum, Apache flute, Apache 1-stringed violin"...; SWF 92.18/C.1
- [Interview with Cathy Giesy], Giesy, Cathy, 1992 August 6; August 6, 1992; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: Contains interview with Cathy Giesy of Amado regarding the Black Christ of Imuris...; SWF 92.19/C.1
- Recuerdos - Memories, Guerrero, Lalo, 1992; Palm Springs, CA., Produced by Dan Guerrero, [p1992?]; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: On cover, photo of Lalo Guerrero...Dates when songs were written and recorded on cover... Recording compiled to commemorate the October 11, 1992, tribute at McCallum Theatre in Palm Desert, California to Lalo Guerrero... Material was gathered from previous recordings in various formats... Pecadora -- Nunca Jamas -- Cancion Mexicana -- Barrio Viejo -- Do you believe in reincarnation? -- Hey Mabel -- Elvis Perez -- El Guiri Guiri -- La Minifalda de Reynalda -- Los Chucos snaves -- Marihuana boogie -- Vamos a bailar -- Pancho Lopez -- Tacos for two -- Pancho Claus -- There's no tortillas -- La Pollera rota -- Tin marin de do pingue -- El Corrido de Delano -- El Chicano --; SWF 92.23/C.1
- Pure cowboy, Easterbrooke, Jim, 1991; Tucson, AZ., Lucky Penny Studios, Produced by J Bar R Productions, p1991; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: Photo of Jim Easterbrook on cover...Cover contains biographical information about Jim Easterbrook and notes about the songs and poems... Performers include: Jim Easterbrook; Renate Easterbrook; Bill Ganz... Dream chasin' -- Cowboy Jack Clead (vocal by Renate Easterbrook) -- I ride Ol' Paint -- Chisholm Trail -- The Store -- Desert dove -- When the works all done -- Cattle business -- My rifle, my pony and me (harmony by Renate Easterbrook) -- Twilight on the trail --Tribute to the cowboy --; SWF 92.25/C.1
- Original music tape #1, Guerrero, Mark Anthony, 1971-1973; Tucson, AZ., Lucky Penny Studios, Produced by J Bar R Productions, p1991; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From cover, tape contains 16 songs... All songs, words and music by Mark Anthony Guerrero... More information available in acquistions file, 92.26/M-1... Lila, love me tonight -- Dare I touch you, Marylou? -- Lonely -- He's an artist -- Walk on down -- I'm a human -- Allesandro -- I'm Brown -- Rock and Roll Queen -- Wild night at the old rest home -- Brown hair growin' -- Livin' off the land -- Greenback blues -- Don't rain on my parade -- Hang on -- Out in the cold --; SWF 92.26/C.1
- Original music tape #2, Guerrero, Mark Anthony, 1972-1985; 1972-1985; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From cover, tape includes 19 songs... All songs, words and music by Mark Anthony Guerrero... More information available in acquisitions file, 92.26/M-1... Nobody's satisfied -- Holy Moses -- Rock and Roll circus -- You gotta thank the Black man (for your Rock and Roll) -- Love lotion -- I'll take Rock and Roll (any ol' time) -- On the boulevard -- Zoot suit -- Pre-columbian dream -- Mihijito -- Fernado, El Toro (Lalo Guerrero, vocal) -- Pre-Columbian dream (Herb Alpert) -- Hollywood -- Song and dance man (written with John Valenzuela) -- Rocking horse cowboy -- The Jerk at the end of the bar -- Raceta de amor (Spanish lyric by Lalo Guerrero) -- Face and heart -- Heart music --; SWF 92.26/C.2
- Original music tape #3, Guerrero, Mark Anthony, 1988-1992; 1988-1992; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From cover, tape contains 17 songs... All words and music by Mark Anthony Guerrero... More information in acqusitions file, 92.26/M-1... On the boulevard -- If I could touch your life -- Latin quarter -- Room for the Latin (in Rock and Roll) -- Whitewash -- The Great mango -- Radio Aztlan -- Orale! -- Amiga -- Jukebox man -- The Quest for love -- Hostage of the heart -- The Ballad of Carlos Almarez -- Days of the Dons -- Mexican moon -- Blood on the sun -- Oh Maria --; SWF 92.26/C.3
- Hecho in Utah (Made in Utah): Latin American music, 1992; Salt Lake City, UT., WT Studios, p1992; 1 sound cassette, analog, vol. 1; Hecho en Utah; NOTES: Hecho en Utah is a project of the Utah Folk Arts Program, funded in part by a grant from the Folk Arts Program, National Endowment for the Arts...Tape is one of a series of three cassettes featuring music of Utah residents that relects Spanish heritage...Extensive description on cover regarding musicians and music...21 songs performed in order by Soul Latino, contemporary Latin; Damaris of Columbia; La Clave, music of the Carribbean; Formula Tres, Peruvian creole music; Grupo Nayra, music of the Bolivian Andes; Los Del Sur, music of Argentina and Uruguay; La Familia Arrambide, music of the Peruvian Andes...; SWF 93.1/C.1
- Hecho en Utah (Made in Utah): Mexican music, 1992; Salt Lake City, UT., WT Studios, p1992; 1 sound cassette, analog; Hecho en Utah, vol. 2; NOTES: Hecho en Utah is a project of the Utah Folk Arts Program, funded in part by a grant form the Folk Arts Program, National Endowment for the Arts... One of a series of three cassettes featuring music of Utah residents that reflect Spanish heritage... In Spanish... Extensive description on cover regarding musicians and music... Includes 23 selections of rancheros, corridos, and boleros, performed in order by: Mariachi Aguilas de Utah; Gomez Family; Magdalena Chavira; Eunesto Rico; Fuego Tropical; Los Mercanarios...; SWF 93.1/C.2
- Hecho en Utah (Made in Utah): Tex-Mex and New Mexican music, 1992; Salt Lake City, UT., WT Studios, p1992; 1 sound cassette, analog; Hecho en Utah, vol.3; NOTES: Hecho en Utah is a project of the Utah Folk ARts Program, funded in part by a grant from the Folk Arts Program, National Endowment for the Arts... One of a series of three cassettes featuring music of Utah residents that reflect Spanish heritage... In Spanish... Extensive description on cover regarding musicians and music... 29 selections are performed in order by Elisa y el Trio Rio Bravo, Tex-Mex music -- Rosina Velasquez de Chavez and Friends, harmonica music of New Mexico -- Vallejos/Herrera Family, songs and dance music of New Mexico -- James Romero y Los Amigos, New Mexican dance music --; SWF 93.1/C.3
- [Performances], Kartcher-Shumway Family, 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From acquisition file: "performances of the Shumway Family with earlier gift of Shumway Family songbook"...; SWF 93.2/C.1
- Yazzie girl, Burch, Sharon, 1989; Phoenix, AZ., Canyon Records Productions, Executive producer, Raymond A. Boley, Produced by Sharon Burch and Robert Doyle, p1989; 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: On cover, Navajo lyrics and English translations; biographical information and colorized photograph of Sharon Burch by Lorenzo Baca... Navajo translations by Marvin Yellowhair... In Navajo... The Rain song (3:47) -- New Born Blessing (3:09) -- Little one (3:21) -- Grandpa's birthday song (3:43) -- Sacred mountain (3:56) -- The Chant (4:49) -- Mother Earth (2:59) -- For this, I am happy (5:25) -- Yazzie girl (4:29) (assistance on chorus lyrics by Max Newton) --; SWF 93.4/C.1
- The Hanging of Eva Dugan, Craver, Al, 1 sound cassette, analog; NOTES: From acquisition file, "The Hanging of Eva Dugan" by Al Craver, probably a pseudoname for Vernon Dalhart... This is a 1930's commerical country "Hillbilly" ballad about an Arizona event...Seven pages of correspondence concerning the hanging and the song located in file, 93.10/C.1...; SWF 93.10/C.1